The Jungle is JUMPIN'!
The Jungle Book is a family, animation, adventure
film directed by Wolfgang Reitherman.
The boy Mowgli makes his way to the man-village with Bagheera, the wise panther.
Along the way he meets jazzy King Louie, the hypnotic snake Kaa and the lovable, happy-go-lucky bear
Baloo, who teaches Mowgli "The Bare Necessities" of life and the true meaning of friendship.
Mowgli the Man Cub (voice), played by Bruce Reitherman.
Baloo the Bear (voice), played by Phil Harris.
Bagheera the Panther (voice), played by Sebastian Cabot.
Shere Khan the Tiger (voice), played by George Sanders.
Kaa the Snake (voice), played by Sterling Holloway.
King Louie of the Apes (voice), played by Louis Prima.
The Jungle Book is a 1967 American animated musical adventure film produced by
Walt Disney Productions and released by Buena Vista Distribution.
Based on the "Mowgli" stories from Rudyard Kipling's 1894 book of the same name, it is the final
animated feature film to be produced by Walt Disney, who died during its production.
It was directed by Wolfgang Reitherman and written by Larry
Clemmons, Ralph Wright, Ken Anderson, and Vance Gerry.
Featuring the voices of Phil Harris, Sebastian Cabot, Louis Prima, George Sanders, and Sterling Holloway, the film's plot follows Mowgli, a feral child raised in the Indian
jungle by wolves, as his friends, Bagheera the panther and Baloo the bear, try to convince him to leave the jungle before the ruthless tiger Shere Khan arrives.
The early versions of both the screenplay and the soundtrack followed Kipling's work more closely, with a dramatic, dark, and sinister
tone, which Disney did not want in his family film, leading to writer Bill Peet and songwriter Terry Gilkyson being replaced.
The Jungle Book was released on October 18, 1967, to positive reception, with acclaim for its soundtrack,
featuring five songs by the Sherman Brothers and one by Gilkyson, "The Bare Necessities".
With a gross of $23.8 million worldwide, the film initially became Disney's second-highest-grossing animated film in the
United States and Canada, the ninth-highest-grossing film of 1967, and was also successful during its re-releases.
The film was also successful throughout the world, becoming
Germany's highest-grossing film by number of admissions.
Disney released a live-action adaptation in 1994 and an animated sequel in 2003; a live-action/animated hybrid
remake directed by Jon Favreau was released in 2016, with a sequel to that film in development.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, narration,
human animal relationship, cartoon, villain.